ERASTUS NJOROGE

Data Analyst / Developer

CONTACT



+254 702 120 703

241-0120 Kenol, Thika-Murang'a Road

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ erastus-njoroge-40817778/

https://github.com/indomit able-core

SKILLS

Debugging

DOM Manipulation

API design knowledge

Hardware and Software installation

Solutions deployment

Proficient in Statistical data analysis

Fast Learner

PROGRAMMING

Expert

Django, Javascript, jQuery, CSS, Python, Postgresql, MySQL MS EXCEL, SPSS, React

Intermediate

Solidity, Ruby on Rails, Angular, Flask, R-studio, Java, C++.

Learning

WordPress, Laravel, Spring Boot

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am an experienced Data Analyst and a Web Developer familiar with wide range of programming utilities and languages. I am Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements and can handle any part of process with ease. I describe myself as a collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities. I am also well versed with the dynamics of IT and strive to give a prompt solution.

EXPERIENCE

VOLUNTEER TECHNICAL MENTOR

Moringa School, Nairobi / March 2022 - Present

- Assessing the responsiveness of the allocated students on their responsiveness to the program.
- Assisting students in debugging programming codes in such languages as CSS, Angular, Javascript, React, Ruby on Rails, Flask, and Django.
- Providing support for students in deploying their projects in in gh-pages, netlify and heroku.
- Providing any other technical support raised by the student.
- Collaborating with Technical Mentors in giving specific student support to specific students as identified in the software development class.
- Providing reports on the status of the student and nature of assistance provided.
- Reviewing the progress of the whole exercise weekly.

REGISRATION ASSISTANT

National Integrated Identity Management System (NIIMS), Kenol / March 2019 – May 2019

- Ensuring the availability of all registration materials assigned during the exercise.
- Filling of the data capture form.
- Transfer of the same information to the biometric kit
- Capturing of biometrics (fingerprints and facial features picture)
- Checking the completeness of the forms to ensure that all questions were asked and that responses were legibly captured
- Forwarding on daily basis to the supervisor all registration kits and forms (filled, unfilled and spoilt)
- Recording any emerging issues and challenges encountered Preparing daily debriefing notes for the supervisor on registration status

MATHEMATICS TEACHER

Karugia Secondary School, Kenol / Sept 2016 – Oct 2016

 Assessed submitted class assignments, determined grades and reviewed work with struggling students to boost success chances

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN MATHEMATICS AND COMPUTER SCIENCE / STATISTICS OPTION

JKUAT, JUJA

2012 - 2016

COURSES

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT / WEB DEVELOPMENT

MORINGA SCHOOL, NAIROBI

May 2021 - Nov 2021

CERTIFIED PUBLIC ACCOUNTANT (CPA)

Thika Institute of Business Studies (TIBS),

THIKA

2016 - 2018

TRAINING

WEB 3 BLOCKCHAIN TECHNOLOGIES

POLYGON | IMPACT+, NAIROBI

29th August 2022 –2nd September 2022

- Utilized multimedia strategies and technology to convey information in fresh and interesting ways.
- Administered assessments and standardized tests to evaluate student progress.
- Diversified teaching techniques and learning tools help students with differing ability levels and varied learning modalities.
- Kept classroom environments consistent and focused on learning by establishing and enforcing clear objectives.
- Supplemented textbook material with approved third-party examples and resources for clarity on difficult topics

ICT ATTACHE'

Smartedge EA LTD, Nairobi / May 2013 - August 2013

- Provided network support and performed troubleshooting to resolve various WAN/LAN connectivity issues.
- Set up hardware and software in optimal configurations to meet network performance requirements.
- Recommended accessories and complementary purchases to boost revenue.
- Offered friendly and efficient service to customers, handled challenging situations with ease.
- Learned new skills and applied to daily tasks to improve efficiency and productivity.
- Responding to other duties allocated by the manager.

MATHEMATICS TEACHER

Muthurumbi Secondary School, Gatundu / May 2012 - Sept 2012

- Initiated communication with students to address learning concerns and offer additional guidance for independent study.
- Helped students make good decisions about course choices for educational and vocational goals.
- Addressed systematic issues with math curriculum by collaborating with colleagues.
- Held regular office hours to assist students struggling with materials.
- Provided meaningful math instruction to improve math skills of children.
- Prepared and implemented lesson plans covering required course topics.
- Developed and distributed study guides to reinforce lecture details and help students with test preparation.
- Implemented peer tutoring system to enhance comprehensive understanding of math techniques and increase student test scores.
- Proctored exams for students to promote educational growth.

REFEREES

Mr. Charles Njuguna

ICT Support, Nairobi Water and Sewerage Company

Email: cndugire@nairobiwater.co.ke

Phone: +254 707 261 561

Mr. Benson Mungai

Software Developer, Safaricom PLC Email: bkmungai@safaricom.co.ke

Phone: +254 717 884 057

Ms Rose Oketch

Senior Technical Mentor, Moringa School Email: rose.oketch@moringaschool.com

Phone: +254 711 895 723